Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth papers, Inclusive: 1826-1965, undated, Bulk: 1930-1943
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
- Collected Materials, 1836-1943, undated; 6; This series contains two document boxes and two oversized boxes.
  - General (8 of 9), undated (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - General (9 of 9), undated (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Advertisements, 1886-1887 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - CAdvertisements, 1887-1940, undated (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Bulletin: Congressional Record, 1929-1935 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Bulletin: Congressional Record, 1936-1941 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1933-1943 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Essay: “A Review of the Geology of the Clovis Finds Reported by Howard and Cotter”, 1937 December 14 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Essay: “Frances Trask”: Emma Burleson, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Essay: “Progress or Retrogress?”: Henry Christian, undated (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Essay: “Something New in Education”: Robert Hutchins, 1933 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Essay: “Tactics of the Air Forces in War”: T.D. Milling, undated (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Essays: General, 1934 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Essays: General, 1935 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Essays: General, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Essays: General (1 of 3), undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Essays: General (2 of 3), undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Essays: General (3 of 3), undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Essays: Randolph Adams, 1937-1939 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Essays: Randolph Adams, 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Lists: General, 1890-1897 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Lists: General (1 of 2), 1898 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Lists: General (2 of 2), 1898 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlets, 1916-1931 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Pamphlets, 1937 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Pamphlets, 1938-1941 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Pamphlets, undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Periodical: Frontier Times, 1940 December (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Poetry, 1916-1938 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Poetry, 1940 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Poetry, 1941-1942, undated (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Poetry, undated (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Speeches (1 of 2), 1934, undated (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Speeches (2 of 2), 1934, undated (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Travel Guide: Germany, 1901 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Travel Guide: Germany, 1902 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Printed Materials, 1924 (Box [1076] OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Printed Materials, 1933-1939 February (Box [1076] OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Printed Materials, 1939 May (Box [1076] OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Printed Materials, 1939 December- 1941, undated (Box [1076 OVZ], Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook: Clippings: Texas History, 1935-1936, undated (Box [1065], Folder 6)
  - Bonds: Union Trust Company, 1902 (Box 32 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Periodicals: General, 1933-1940, undated (Box 32 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Periodicals: Christian Call, 1929 (Box 32 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - Periodicals: The Daily Lariat, 1936-1942 (Box 32 OVZ, Folder 10)
  - Periodicals: Waco Farm and Labor Journal, 1937-1943 (Box 32 OVZ, Folder 11)
- Literary Productions, 1905-1945, undated; 7; This series contains four document boxes and two oversized boxes.
  This series contains addresses, manuscripts, essays, and other literary productions produced by or directly pertaining to Dr. Kenneth Aynesworth. Medical and educational essays are particularly well-represented in the series. The materials are in good condition.
  - Address: “Division of Labor in the Machine Age”: K.H. Aynesworth, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Address: “Education in a Democracy”: K.H. Aynesworth: Philosopher’s Club, 1932 October 10 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Address: Funeral: Kenneth Aynesworth, 1944-1945 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Address: “Higher Education and the Democratic Ideal”: Kenneth Aynesworth: University of Texas, 1938 August 29 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Address: Kenneth Aynesworth: Southwestern University, 1941 December 2 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Address: Kenneth Aynesworth: Texas Dental College, 1942 June 8 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Address: Memorial for Dr. James Thompson: Kenneth Aynesworth, 1927 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Address: “The Cavemen of 1939”: Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth, 1939 March 10 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Address: “The Conditions of the Peace”: Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth, 1943 May 11 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Address: “The Doctor, Then and Now”: K.H. Aynesworth, 1942 March 20 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Address: “The Little Boy’s Journey”: K.H. Aynesworth, 1939 September 29 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Address: “The Physician as a Citizen”: Kenneth Aynesworth: University of Texas: Medical Department, 1929 May 31 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Addresses: General, 1917 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Addresses: General, 1930 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Addresses: General, 1931 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Addresses: General, 1932 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Addresses: General, 1933- 1940 July (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Addresses: General, 1940 October, undated (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Addresses: General, undated (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Clippings: General, 1940 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Commencement Addresses, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Commencement Addresses, 1941 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Commencement Addresses, 1942 March (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Commencement Addresses, 1942, undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Drama: “It’s All in a Day’s Work”: K.H. Aynesworth, 1934 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Essay: “Acute Osteomyelitis”: Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth, 1916 June (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Essay: “Education in the Modern Totalitarian State”: Kenneth Aynesworth, 1938 January 20 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Essay: Phi Beta Kappa Fraternity, 1934 May 14 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Essay: “Philip Nolan and his Companions”: J.A. Quintero, 1936 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Essay: “Renovating Ruth”, undated (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Essay: “Stricture of the Common Bile Duct”: K.H. Aynesworth, 1934 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Essay: “The Cervicobrachial Syndrome”, 1940 May (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Essay: “The Cervicobrachial Syndrome”, 1940 July -1941 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Essay: “The Cervicobrachial Syndrome”, 1943, undated (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Essay: “The Cervicobrachial Syndrome”, undated (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Essay: “The Layman’s Viewpoint of a Modern University, Its Missions, Its Methods, Its Results”: Kenneth Aynesworth, 1934 April 17 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Essays: General, 1927 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Essays: General, 1931-1932 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Essays: General, 1934 January- March (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Essays: General, 1934 October- 1935 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Essays: General, 1936-1938 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Essays: General, 1938 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Essays: General, 1939 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Essays: General, 1940 March- April (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Essays: General, 1940 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Essays: General, 1941-1943 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Essays: General (1 of 5), undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Essays: General (2 of 5), undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Essays: General (3 of 5), undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Essays: General (4 of 5), undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Essays: General (5 of 5), undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Essays: Medical, 1905-1911 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Essays: Medical, 1912-1913 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Essays: Medical, 1925-1926 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Essays: Medical, 1926-1931 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Essays: Medical, 1933 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Essays: Medical, 1935-1937 May (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Essays: Medical, 1937 November- 1938 May (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Essays: Medical, 1938 June-November (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Essays: Medical, 1942-1943 (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Essays: Medical (1 of 2), undated (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - Essays: Medical (2 of 2), undated (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - Manuscript: “Biological Basis of Human Conduct”, undated (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Manuscript: “Education in a Democracy”: K.H. Aynesworth: Philosopher’s Club (1 of 3), 1932 October 10 (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - Manuscript: “Education in a Democracy”: K.H. Aynesworth: Philosopher’s Club (2 of 3), 1932 October 10 (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Manuscript: “Education in a Democracy”: K.H. Aynesworth: Philosopher’s Club (3 of 3), 1932 October 10 (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (1 of 16), undated (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (2 of 16), undated (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (3 of 16), undated (Box 29, Folder 32)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (4 of 16), undated (Box 29, Folder 33)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (5 of 16), undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (6 of 16), undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (7 of 16), undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (8 of 16), undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (9 of 16), undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (10 of 16), undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (11 of 16), undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (12 of 16), undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (13 of 16), undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (14 of 16), undated (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (15 of 16), undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript: “On Pain” (16 of 16), undated (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Printed Materials, 1931, undated (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Publications, 1930-1938 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Publications, 1939-1940 January (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Publications, 1940 February (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Publications, 1940 March-April (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Publications, 1940 May-1943, undated (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Publications, undated (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Blueprints: Servants House, undated (Box [1076] OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Publications: Public Housing, 1941, undated (Box 32 OVZ, Folder 12)
  - Publications: Waco Tribune Herald: Waco Chamber of Commerce, 1939-1943 (Box 32 OVZ, Folder 13)
- Personal, 1860-1943, undated; 8; This series contains three document boxes and two oversized boxes.
  This series contains personal materials belonging to Kenneth Aynesworth including records of his membership in various local and medical organizations, legal papers, and certificates. The materials are in average to good condition.
  - Memberships, 1906-1943, undated; 1; This subseries is comprised of three document boxes.
    This series contains correspondence and printed materials pertaining to Dr. Kenneth Aynesworth's memberships in various medical and local organizations. Some of the organizations featured include the American College of Surgeons, the Central Texas Archaeological Society, the Southern Surgical Association, the Texas Academy of Science, the Texas State Historical Association, and the Waco City Club. The materials are in good condition.
    The folders within this subseries are organized alphabetically by the name of the organization to which Aynesworth was a member.
    - American College of Surgeons, 1913-1937 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - American College of Surgeons, 1940-1943, undated (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Central Texas Archaeological Society, 1933-1935 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Central Texas Archaeological Society, 1936-1940 February (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Central Texas Archaeological Society, 1940 March-October (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Central Texas Archaeological Society, 1941 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Central Texas Archaeological Society, 1942, undated (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - National, 1906-1941 (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - National, 1942-1943, undated (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Philosopher’s Club, 1934-1943 (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Philosopher’s Club, 1943 (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - Southern Surgical Association, 1925-1933 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Southern Surgical Association, 1935-1937 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - Southern Surgical Association, 1938-1939 (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - Southern Surgical Association, 1940-1941 (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - Southern Surgical Association, 1943, undated (Box 30, Folder 35)
    - Texas, 1925-1930 (Box 30, Folder 36)
    - Texas, 1930-1935 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Texas, 1936-1939 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Texas, 1940-1941 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Texas, 1942-1943 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Texas, undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Texas Academy of Science, 1931-1936 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Texas Academy of Science, 1937-1938 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Texas Academy of Science, 1938-1939 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Texas Academy of Science, 1939-1941 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Texas Academy of Science, 1942-1943 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Texas State Historical Association, 1926-1937 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Texas State Historical Association, 1938-1943 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Texas State Historical Association, undated (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Texas Surgical Society, 1932-1939 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Texas Surgical Society, 1940-1943, undated (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Twelfth District Central Texas Medical Society, 1931-1935 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Twelfth District Central Texas Medical Society, 1936-1940 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Twelfth District Central Texas Medical Society, 1941-1943 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Waco City Club, 1929-1930 June (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Waco City Club, 1930 August- 1931 February (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Waco City Club, 1931 March-August (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Waco City Club, 1931 September-1932 March (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Waco City Club, 1932 April-July (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - General, 1860-1943, undated; 2; This subseries is housed in one document box and two oversized boxes.
    The following subseries contains personal materials pertaining to Kenneth Aynesworth and his family. Of particular importance are the legal documents from the late nineteenth century, a bond purchased by Aynesworth during World War II, and a certificate bestowed upon Aynesworth by the United States embassy in Berlin. The materials are in average condition.
    This subseries is organized alphabetically by the type of material.
    - Baylor University, 1896 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Baylor University, 1897 February-March (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Baylor University, 1897 April (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Baylor University, 1897 May (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth, 1878-1939, undated (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Legal Papers, 1860-1901 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - Legal Papers, 1905-1939 (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - Legal Papers, 1943, undated (Box 31, Folder 31)
    - Bond: Liberty Loan: Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth, undated (Box [1076] OVZ, Folder 6)
    - Certificate: United States Embassy, 1901 (Box 32 OVZ, Folder 14)